Josh Gottheil Collection ARC.0150
Library and Archives
- Correspondence for proposed events, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Pollstar, 1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Concert One Productions, 1988-1989
  - Page from "The Daily Illini" with They Might Be Giants advertisement, 1988 November 2 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 61)
  - Flyer for They Might Be Giants at Mabel's, 1988 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 1)
  - Poster for They Might Be Giants at Mabel's, 1988 November 2 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 33)
  - Ticket for They Might Be Giants at Mabel's, 1988 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 2)
  - Flyer for Concert One Productions, 1988 November 2-1988 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 3)
  - Poster for Let's Active and Velvet Elvis at Mabel's, 1988 November 6 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 34)
  - Poster for Timbuk 3 with Semi-Twang, 1988 November 13 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 35)
  - Sonnenberg, John. "Timbuk 3." The Daily Illini Arts and Entertainment Directory, 1988 November 11 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 62)
  - Ticket for Timbuk 3 and Semi-Twang at Mabel's, 1988 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 4)
  - Sonnenberg, Jim. "Timbuk 3 gives far-out show." The Daily Illini, 1988 November 15 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 63)
  - Ticket for, and handwritten note to Josh from, Jonathan Richman at Mabel's, 1988 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 5-6)
  - Ticket for Jane's Addiction at Mabel's, 1988 December 2 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 7)
  - Poster for Scrawl, He's Drunk, 1988 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 76)
  - Photocopied flyer for the Cubby Bear, Chicago, including ad for Friends of Josh Gottheil present "A Benefit for the Leukemia Society", 1989 March 3-1989 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 8)
  - Announcement for "A Benefit for the Leukemia Society at Cubby Bear," Pollstar, 13., 1989 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 9)
  - Faxed press release for "A Benefit for the Leukemia Society", 1989 March 2 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 10)
  - Photocopied article, "Reader's Guide to the Music Scene," mentioning "A Benefit for the Leukemia Society", circa 1989 March 5 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 11)
  - Correspondence from Marty Perez to Josh Gottheil, includes photograph from "A Benefit for the Leukemia Society," featuring Peter Holsapple and Peter Buck, 1989 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 30, Object 12-14)
- Guest lists, ticket sales, etc., 1988, 1997, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- In Memoriam, 1989-2009
  - Calendar, Madonna, 1989 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 47)
  - The News-Gazette Weekend, 1989 May 12 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 8)
  - Photographic copy of flyer for Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund benefit concert featuring Throwing Muses at Mabel's, 1989 May 14 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 1a)
  - The Daily Illini Arts & Entertainment Directory, 1989 May (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 64)
  - Leukemia Society, Illinois Chapter. "Central Illinois Branch says farewell to a hero." Leukemia Society News, 8, no. 2, 1989 Summer (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 1b)
  - 1989 September 27 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 36)
  - Color photograph of the Flaming Lips in the Gottheil home, 1989 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 1c)
    With road manager (name unknown); Margaret Dees, principal Yankee Ridge School (Urbana, Ill.); and Lois Hickey, teacher, Yankee Ridge School.
  - The Daily Illini, 1989 September 28 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 65)
  - Newspaper advertisement for Pixies concert for the Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund for Lymphoma Research, Foellinger Auditorium, 1989 October 13 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 66)
  - Neuhaus, Tad. "Josh Gottheil." Star Course News Mag., 1989 October (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 1d)
  - Prospectus, 23, no. 14, 1989 November 8 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 67)
  - The Daily Illini Arts & Entertainment Directory, 1989 November 10-16 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 68)
  - Flyer for the Pixies concert for the Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund for Lymphoma Research at Foellinger Auditorium, 1989 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 2-3)
  - Poster for the Pixies, concert for the Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund for Lymphoma Research, 1989 November 12 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 37)
  - Ticket for the Pixies at Foellinger Auditorium, 1989 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 4)
  - Jinks, Michael. "Pixies put on piercing performance." The Daily Illini, 1989 November 14 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 69)
  - Calendar, Pixies, 1990 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 48)
  - Advertisement for Record Service 20th birthday CD, The Daily Illini, 1990 May 3 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 38)
  - Wood, Paul. "Local bands to jam Friday night at Localpalooza." The Champaign-Urbana News-Gazette, C-6., 1994 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 5)
  - Berlin, Jonathon. "Concert will aid cancer research." The Daily Illini, 124, no. 4: 1, 6. [photocopy], 1994 September 23 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 39)
  - "Localpalooza: A Marathon of Bands." Student Life: 68. [photocopy], 1994 September (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 40)
  - Poster for Localpalooza, 1994 September 23 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 41)
  - Benson, Anitra. "Tournament, bands assist Gottheil fund." The Daily Illini, 1996 October 2 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 70)
  - "Four bands to play at Sept. 21 benefit." The News-Gazette, 1997 September 6 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 77)
  - Kacich, Tom. "Concert set to raise funds, remember Josh." The News-Gazette, 1997 September 14 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 78)
  - Diversions, September 19, 1997 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 71)
  - "Sarge, Menthol, Hum, Luna." The Octopus, 1997 September 19 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 9)
  - Poster for Sarge, Menthol, Hum, and Luna at Josh's Jam, a rock and roll benefit for the Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund for Lymphoma Research, Foellinger Auditorium, 1997 September 21 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 72)
  - Ticket for Luna, Hum, Sarge, and Menthol at Foellinger Auditorium, Benefit for Josh's Fund, 1997 September 21 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 6)
  - McCabe, Emily. "Sarge, Menthol, Luna and Hum September 19 Foellinger Auditorium." The News-Gazette., 1997 September 25 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 7-8)
  - Diversions, 1997 October 17 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 73)
  - Section from The Octopus announcing Benefit Show for Josh Gottheil at Mabel's, 1997 October 17 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 10)
  - "Tanya Donelly, Lanterna, Space-Age Polymers," The Octopus with an article announcing the benefit for the Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund, 1997 October 17 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 11)
  - Ticket for Tanya Donelly, Lanterna, and TBA at Mabel's, for the Josh Gottheil Memorial Fund, 1997 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 9)
  - The Octopus, 1997 October 24 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 12)
  - Poster for Death to the Pixies, 1997 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 75)
  - Fletcher, Elayne. “There's Something About Josh.” Days of Speed and Slowtime Mondays (blog), http://daysofspeed.blogspot.com/2007/04/theres-something-about-josh.html., 2007 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 10)
  - “Josh Gottheil...who is he?” openingbands.com, http://openingbands.com/forums/viewthread.race?MessageID=72580., 2007 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 11)
  - Editors. "Travel Back to 1993 Sunday at The Highdive." Smile Politely., 2008 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 12)
  - Michael, Troy. "The Legacy of Josh Gottheil Lives on with a Benefit Show Featuring the Poster Children." Innocent Words., 2009 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 13)
  - Michael, Troy. "Carrying on a local legacy." The News-Gazette, 2009 May 21-27 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 13)
  - "Josh Gottheil Memorial Concert Featuring The Outnumbered, Lonely Trailer, Cowboy X, and Poster Children." the217.com., 2009 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 14)
  - St. Clair, Katy. "Josh Gottheil Was in the Room.", 2009 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 15)
  - Reedy, Brian. "Studio visit." The News-Gazette, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 32, Object 16)
- Mabel's concert calendars, March-November
  - Mabel's schedule, March (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 69)
  - Mabel's "Revue", May (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 70)
  - Poster with Mabel's concert calendar, June (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 71)
  - Mabel's "Revue", August (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 72)
  - Mabel's "Revue" newsletter, September (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 73)
  - Mabel's schedule, October (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 74)
  - Mabel's "Revue", November (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 74)
  - Mabel's schedule, November (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 75)
- Miscellaneous posters, March 19-November 22, undated
  - Robyn Hitchcock and the Egyptians with Glass Eye at Berkeley Square, March 19 (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 76)
  - Violent Femmes at Freeborn Hall, University of California-Davis, April 17 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 42)
  - Dead Kennedys, Part Time Christians, Special Forces, and Jungle Studs at Ruthie's, August 28 (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 77)
  - Dead Kennedys, Stoney Burke, Rhythm Pigs, Kamper Van Beethoven, and Morlocks at Mabuhay, October 18 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 43)
  - Circle Jerks, Descendents, and 7 Seconds at The Farm, November 22 (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 44)
  - EP by the Permanent Buzz [signed by Geoff Merritt?], undated (Box-folder OS1-1, Object 78)
  - The Farmboys, Ditch Valley, undated (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 45)
  - S.W.A.N.S. album, undated (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 46)
- Pixies: Nine Postcards (illustrating lyrics from the "Doolittle" album), undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Pixies: Nine Posters (illustrating lyrics from the "Doolittle" album), undated (Box-folder OS1-2, Object 14)
- Contracts, 1986-1988
  - Adolescents, Scab with Pied Piper Productions for October 22, 1986 at Channing Murray Foundation, 1986 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - 7Seconds with Other Side Productions for December 14, 1986 at Channing Murray Foundation, 1986 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mojo Nixon, Skid Roper with Venture Bookings for April 26, 1987 at Trito's Uptown, 1987 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Flaming Lips with Bulging Eye Booking for September 1, 1987 at Trito's Uptown, 1987 July 31 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Ben Vaughn Combo with Venture Bookings for October 18, 1987 at Trito's Uptown, 1987 September 15 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Drivin' N Cryin' with Venture Bookings for November 16, 1987 at Trito's Uptown, 1987 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mojo Nixon and Skid Roper with Venture Bookings for May 5, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 March 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Billy Bragg with Music Business Agency for May 4, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Flaming Lips with Bulging Eye Booking for April 24, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Michele Shocked with Music Business Agency for May 4, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 April 19 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Pixies with The Labor Board for June 1, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 May 10 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Royal Crescent Mob, My Dad Is Dead, Bastro, The Membranes with Venture Bookings for performance dates between July 27-August 2, 1988 at Trito's Uptown, 1988 July 12-1988 August 2 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Donor's Note
    On the basis of other materials, this band appeared not on the date of the contract but on July 31, 1988, along with My Dad Is Dead, possibly instead of Bastro.
  - Soul Asylum with Triad Artists for September 22, 1988, 1988 August 18 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Living Colour with Triad Artists for September 18, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 August 26 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alice Donut with Bulging Eye Booking for September 18, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - A Flock of Seagulls with Frontier Booking and Anthony Poulos Productions for October 26, 1988 at Avalon Nightclub (Chicago, Illinois), 1988 September 26 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Velvet Elvis with Frontier Booking for November 6, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Jonathan Richman with Triad Artists for November 17, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Timbuk 3 with Triad Artists for November 13, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 October 6 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Jane's Addiction with Triad Artists for December 2, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Includes a transmittal letter and promotional photographs but no contract.
  - Let's Active for November 6, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 September 29 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Contract with Frontier Booking.
  - They Might Be Giants for November 2, 1988 at Mabel's, 1988 October 3 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Contract with Triad Artists.
  - Soul Asylum for November 9, 1988 at Mississippi Nights, 1988 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Contract with Triad Artists. On the basis of other materials, this band appeared not on the date of the contract but on September 22, 1988.
  - Royal Crescent Mob for October 30, 1988 at Chin's Wok and Roll, 1988 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Inventory of Josh Gottheil's Music Related Belongings, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  This inventory and biography was created by the donor. Please note that not all items on the inventory were donated to the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame and Museum, Inc.
- Audio recordings, 1982-1988, undated
  - Josh Session, WEFT, 1987 April 9 (Box 2, Cassette 1, Box 3, Disk 1)
    Playlist
    Side B: "Crazy Dan" - Scratch Acid "Greatest Gift" - Scratch Acid "Club Med Sucks" - Camper Van Beethoven "Inside a Fireball" - Hunters and Collectors "Rio" - Nip Drivers "Living Daylight" - Hunters and Collectors "Jackie's Gone" - The Vertebrats "I Must Not Think Bad Thoughts" - X "Victory Parade" - Snake Corps "Flesh on Flesh" - Snake Corps "Hiroshima Mon Amour" - Ultravox "Taxi" - Harry Chapin
    Side A: "Taxi" (cont'd) - Harry Chapin "All Mod Cons" - The Jam "To Be Someone" - The Jam "English Rose" - The Jam "Mr. Clean" - The Jam "Praise" - 7 Seconds "Night Away" - 7 Seconds "Not Just Boys Fun" - 7 Seconds [unidentified track] "Stuffin' Martha's Muffin" - Mojo Nixon and Skid Roper "Staring at Sound" - Flaming Lips
    Existence and Location of Copies note
    An access copy on CD was created for this audio tape and included in the donation.
    This was likely Gottheil's first appearance on WEFT-FM, while he was still training, and he was a guest on his friend Renee's show. During the recording, they chat every so often in between songs. The included playlist was most likely written by Renee. The playlist can also be found in one of Gottheil's journals, for shows between July 30, 1987 and July 20, 1988.
  - WEFT, 1987 April [?] (Box 3, Disk 2, Folder 1, Box 2, Cassette 2)
    Side A: "This is the Day" - The The "Out For a Walk" - Flaming Lips "Cherry Lee" - Didjits "My Baby, She's Alright" - Didjits "I Kill Spies" - Agent Orange "I'm in Love (with that Song)" - [unidentified] "Alec's Children" - The Replacements "Listen to the Music" - Thelonius Monster "Walk on Water" - Thelonius Monster "If I" - Thelonius Monster "Moments of Love" - Art of Noise "Dominique" - Dynamic Duo
    Side B: "Fast, Fierce and Funny" - Cameo "Dominique" - Dynamic Duo "You Need Another Lover Like a Hole in the Head" - [unidentified] "Walking on your Hands" - Red Lorry Yellow Lorry "Kangaroo" - This Mortal Coil "Lights, the Sound, the Rhythm and the Noise" - Flipper "This Town is our Town" - [unidentified] "No Man's Land" - [unidentified] "You Talk Tonight" - Red Pyjamas "Paris, Texas" - Ry Cooder [unidentified track] [unidentified track]
    Gottheil's friend and percussionist, Randy Seals, is a guest on this show. The included playlist and transcript were created by donor Diane Gottheil.
    An access copy on CD was created for this audio tape and is included in the collection.
  - WEFT, 1987 June 4 (Box 2, Cassette 3, Box 3, Disk 3)
  - WEFT, 1987 June 11 (Box 2, Disk 4, Box 3, Cassette 4)
  - WEFT, 1988 July 20 (Box 2, Cassette 5, Box 3, Disk 5)
  - WEFT 1, undated (Box 3, Disk 6, Box 2, Cassette 6)
  - WEFT 2, undated (Box 2, Cassette 7, Box 3, Disk 7)
  - U2 live at University of Illinois Auditorium, 1982 February 23 (Box 3, Disk 8, Box 2, Cassette 8)
  - Permanent Buzz live, 1983 June 24 (Box 3, Disk 9, Box 2, Cassette 9)
  - Dangerous Acquaintances live at Mabel's, 1984 August 7 (Box 3, Disk 10, Box 2, Cassette 10)
  - Robyn Hitchcock and the Egyptians live at Mabel's, 1985 November 19 (Box 3, Disk 11, Box 2, Cassette 11)
  - Buckethead live at benefit for No More Censorship Defense Fund at the Channing-Murray Foundation, 1987 Feburary 8 (Box 2, Cassette 12, Box 3, Disk 12)
  - Big Black live at Channing-Murray Foundation, 1987 May 3 (Box 3, Disk 13, Box 2, Cassette 13)
  - Firehose live at Mabel's, 1987 November (Box 3, Disk 14, Box 2, Cassette 14)
  - Pixies live in Boston, 1988 September (Box 3, Disk 15, Box 2, Cassette 15)
  - The Signs live, undated (Box 3, Disk 16, Box 2, Cassette 16)
  - Hunkpapa: Josh's New Muses Tape compiled by Tanya Donelly, circa 1988 December (Box 2, Cassette 17, Box 3, Disk 17)
    Side A: "Devil's Roof" "Bea" "Dizzy" "No Parachutes" "Dragonhead" "Say Goodbye"
    Side B: "Fall Down" "I'm Alive" "Angel" "Mania" "The Burrow" "Take"
    CD Extra: "Santa Claus" "Dizzy" - Edited single version Tanya saying hello Songs from my floor
    An access copy on CD has been created for this audio tape.